Guide to the James Duane Livingston III Family Papers 1718-1999 MS 3144
New-York Historical Society
- Series V. "James Duane Livingston III (1930–[2019])," part two, 1965-1970
  - [James Duane Livingston III. Glenville Town Council run (1st)], 1967 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - [James Duane Livingston III. Glenville Town Council run (2nd)], 1969 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - [Glenville sesquicentennial], 1969-1970 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Series VI. "Ancestors of Florence Boullee Livingston: Jugneits, Schmidlings, Boullees, Engelhardts", 1786-1999
  Documentation of the German-immigrant ancestry of James Duane Livingston III's mother, Florence Josephine (Boullee) Livingston (1892–1983). Includes a number of baptism, confirmation, and marriage certificates in German, as well as a series of letters, also in German, from Friedrich Jugneit (1837–1901) to his daughter, Emily Charlotte (Jugneit) Boullee (1866–1957). Several narratives illustrate the relationships among the Boullee, Engelhardt, Jugneit, and Schmidling families (see Box 3, Folders 5, 6, and 24).
  With the exception of loose photographs moved from the front binder pocket to join duplicates inside folders, the documents in Series VI are sorted in the order imposed by James Duane Livingston III.
  - [Title page], undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - James Duane Livingston III. "Travels and Travails of Friedrich Jugneit (1837-1901)", 1999 July 30 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - James Duane Livingston III. "My Grandparents" [maternal], 1999 August 29 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - [Map of East Prussia], undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - [Tax records, Lindendorf, East Prussia], 1789/1801, 1827 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    In German.
  - [Friedrich Jugneit and Maria Schmidling marriage certificate], 1864 March 13 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - [Maria Schmidling confirmation certificate], 1860 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - [Emilie Charlotte Jugneit baptism certificate], 1867 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - [Emilie Charlotte Jugneit confirmation certificate], 1880 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - [Friedrich and Mary (Schmidling) Jugneit decree of divorce], 1874 August 30 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - [Mary Schmidling Jugneit (later Scheer) custody of Emilie Charlotte Jugneit], [1874?] (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - [Mary Ecanoher Schmidling newspaper article and death certificate], 1901-1902 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - James Duane Livingston III. "Letters from Friedrich" [description], 1999 March (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - [Friedrich Jugneit letter 1], 1870s (Box 3, Folder 17)
    In German, with transcription and translation.
  - [Friedrich Jugneit letter 2], 1870s (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - [Friedrich Jugneit letter 3], 1874 April 22 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - [Friedrich Jugneit letter 4], [1901] March 16 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - [Friedrich Jugneit letter 5], 1901 July 12 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    In German, with translation.
  - [Friedrich Jugneit letter 6], 1901 July 28 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - [Friedrich Jugneit death record and cemetery map], 1978 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - James Duane Livingston III. "Wilhelm and Augusta Boullee of New Hamburg, Ontario, and their descendants" [original + photocopy], 1981 February (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - [Boullee family photograph, men], 1905 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - [Boullee family photograph, women], undated (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - [Eli Emilius Boullee pharmacy license], 1891 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - [Emily Charlotte (Jugneit) Boullee cabinet card photographs] (2), undated (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - [Emily Charlotte (Jugneit) Boullee 80th birthday photographs], 1946 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - [Emily Charlotte (Jugneit) Boullee obituary, cemetery monument receipt, and Green-Wood Cemetery ephemera], 1901, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - [Boullee family burials in Riverside Cemetery, New Hamburg, Ontario], undated (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - [Loose photographs from front binder pocket], undated (Box 3, Folder 32)
- Series VII. "Florence Josephine Boullee Livingston (1892–1983) & her brother William H. Boullee (1894–1955)"
  Biographical documentation of James Duane Livingston III's mother, Florence Josephine (Boullee) Livingston (1892–1983) and her sole sibling, William Henry August Boullee (1894–1955). Includes Florence's baptism and confirmation certificates, her early driver's license, wedding photographs, and awards from the American Legion Auxiliary. William Boullee is represented by a few World War I service records, an end-of-life letter to his sister, and an obituary.
  With the exception of loose photographs moved from the back binder pocket to join duplicates inside folders, the documents in Series VII are sorted in the order imposed by James Duane Livingston III.
  - [Title page], undated (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - [Florence Josephine Boullee baptism certificate], 1892 October 9 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - [Florence Josephine Boullee confirmation certificate], 1906 April 8 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - [Florence Josephine Boullee report card and autograph album leaf], 1905, 1906 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - [Florence Josephine Boullee diploma, P.S. 19, Brooklyn], 1906 June 29 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - John B. Cottrell, letter of recommendation for Florence Josephine Boullee, 1906 September 25 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - [Florence Josephine Boullee evening school certificate], 1907 May (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - [Florence Josephine Boullee driver's license and registration], 1921, circa 1980 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - [Florence Josephine Boullee photograph], undated (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Albert E. Kleinert letter to Florence Josephine Boullee re: 3303 Avenue J, Brooklyn, 1923 April 10 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - [James Duane Livingston Jr. and Florence Josephine Boullee wedding invitation and marriage certificate], 1924 September 13 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - [Florence Josephine (Boullee) Livingston wedding photographs], [1924 September] (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - [Map of summer home, Weston, Connecticut], [circa 1940] (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - [American Legion Auxiliary programs], 1925/35, 1940 (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - [West Indies Cruise, S.S. Nieuw Amsterdam, photographs and partial program], 1965 October (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - [Florence Josephine (Boullee) Livingston passport], 1970-1975 (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - [Florence Josephine (Boullee) Livingston death notices and son's remarks at funeral], 1983 July 21-22 (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - [James Duane Livingston III correspondence re: Livingston chairs donated to Gracie Mansion Conservancy], 1983 August 26, November 16 (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - [Florence Josephine (Boullee) Livingston. American Legion Auxiliary awards], 1969, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - [Florence Josephine (Boullee) Livingston. American Legion Auxiliary "Les Chapeaux Departemental Passe" pin], 1980 (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - [Florence Josephine (Boullee) Livingston photographs], undated (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - [Florence Josephine (Boullee) Livingston death certificate], 1983 July 19/21 (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - [William Boullee. Promotion to sergeant], 1916 September 15 (Box 3, Folder 55)
  - [William Boullee. Field Service postcard and letter re: injury], 1918 October 7, November 28 (Box 3, Folder 56)
  - [William Boullee. Commission as second lieutenant], 1918 April 19 (Box 3, Folder 57)
  - [William Boullee. Replacement discharge papers of 1918 and 1920], 1950 April 3 (Box 3, Folder 58)
  - [William Boullee and Sally Allen, wedding invitation (1931 July 3) and church register extract], 1931, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 59)
  - William Boullee letter to Florence Josephine (Boullee) Livingston, [1955] December 12 (Box 3, Folder 60)
  - [William Boullee obituary, memorial program, condolence letter], 1955 December (Box 3, Folder 61)
  - [Loose photographs from back binder pocket], 1911-1942, undated (Box 3, Folder 62)